<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Ellis County Real Estate Podcast with Krissy Mireles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Holmquist & Associates Realty - your professional Ellis County Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Krissy Mireles</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-09-05 10:55:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Krissy Mireles</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>krissy@krissym.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Krissy Mireles</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Ellis County Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Holmquist & Associates Realty - your professional Ellis County Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Navigating the Market as a Contingency Buyer</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/navigating-the-market-as-a-contingency-buyer.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-27 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Navigating+the+Market+as+a+Contingency+Buyer+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

A lot of people don’t have the means to rent or to put their possessions into storage while they search for a new home; using a contingency contract allows them to move from one property to another without making a double move.

In today’s second installment in my series on contingency contracts, I’ll show you how to prepare your home if you’re considering going through with this ‘domino deal’ (click here to see my video on home staging):

If you’re going to navigate the marketplace as a seller with a contingency contract, it’s almost mandatory that you put your home in its best light. You’ll need to price your home correctly per its market value, or perhaps even a little below. That way, you can get your property under contract with a buyer as quickly as possible and a higher chance of the seller accepting your offer.

“Never reschedule buyers when they ask to view your home; let them come as they deem fit.”

To position your home in the market properly, you’ll also need to do more than price it correctly and stage it—you’ll also need to have a very, very flexible schedule for showings. Never reschedule buyers when they ask to view your home; let them come as they deem fit. You’re trying to generate an offer quickly so that you can get to the next one, and delaying their visits will not only extend the time period in which you need to sell your home, but it may also cause buyers to pursue other options.

When you do find a home that you love, you’ll also need to structure your offer depending on its price point. If you’re shopping in, say, the $275,000-or-below range and the home you find is in good condition, you’ll probably find some competition in the form of multiple-offer situations. Since you’re a contingency buyer, you’ll need to put your best foot forward to have the seller even consider your offer. You’ll have a harder time in a multiple-offer situation if you don’t have a buyer for your current home by the time you place an offer on the home you’re attempting to purchase.

In my next video, I’ll discuss more about how to structure an offer so that yours wins out amidst a crowd of competing buyers.

I hope you found this information valuable! If you have any questions or comments about contingency contracts, feel free to reach out to me.  I’m always available for you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Navigating+the+Market+as+a+Contingency+Buyer+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Navigating+the+Market+as+a+Contingency+Buyer+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a homebuyer who’s looking to purchase a new home via contingency contract, here’s some valuable information about navigating the marketplace.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a homebuyer who’s looking to purchase a new home via contingency contract, here’s some valuable information about navigating the marketplace.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Navigating the Contingency Contract</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/navigating-the-contingency-contract.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-10 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Navigating+the+Contingency+Contract+(2).mp4</guid>
        <description>

You’re ready to put your home on the market and make a move, but you need the proceeds from your sale to go toward your next home purchase. 

If you don’t want to do a double-move or you don’t have the time or resources to move into a temporary rental, you need to know how to navigate the contingency contract. 

I can tell you from experience that, depending on your price range, contingency contracts can be super stressful. There are many sellers with contingency contracts trying to locate properties in the $250,000-and-below range, and the majority of them have to compete in multiple-offer situations against non-contingent offers.

“If you don’t want to do a double-move or you don’t have the time or resources to move into a temporary rental, you need to know how to navigate the contingency contract.”

This is why I’m starting a series dedicated to the ins and outs of the contingency contract—to teach you how to present this type of offer in its best light so that you sell your first home for top dollar and purchase your next one without needing to do the double-move. 

The first video will explain how to position your current home on the market successfully. After that, we’ll talk about how you can make your best offer possible. So stay tuned to learn everything you need to know about this topic. 

If you have any questions or any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Navigating+the+Contingency+Contract+(2).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Navigating+the+Contingency+Contract+(2).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>By knowing how to navigate the contingency contract, you can avoid the dreaded double-move.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>By knowing how to navigate the contingency contract, you can avoid the dreaded double-move.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Staging Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-importance-of-staging-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-08 08:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/The+Importance+of+Staging+Your+Home+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve been selling real estate for over 25 years and in that time, I’ve learned many tips and tricks about how to get homes sold for top dollar with the least amount of inconvenience to our sellers. I went and researched home staging, and found that a survey of 4,500 homes that were staged said that 68% of them sold for at least 9% more than a non-staged neighbor’s.

I truly believe the difference can come down to staging when it comes to selling for top dollar. However, I don’t think you need to spend thousands or even hundreds with a professional home stager. They do a fantastic job, but I think soft staging your home with your own things can be successful as well.

“Soft staging is the way to go.”

Soft staging can make a huge difference in the way your home is perceived. All you really need to do is declutter, depersonalize, pay attention to the details and the lighting, and that can change the ambience of your home drastically. When agents are showing homes, they could be showing anywhere from three to five a day, so they don’t have time to stage it themselves. To prepare your home to put it on the market, I think that soft staging is the way to go. Perception becomes reality. Organize your closet and your garage and that will go a long way.

You don’t have to be an organized person to do this. As long as your home is organized while you’re showing it, buyers will pay more money because they get the perception that your home is well-maintained.

I hope you found this information on staging helpful. If you have any questions for me or need any help staging your own property before you list it on the market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/The+Importance+of+Staging+Your+Home+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/The+Importance+of+Staging+Your+Home+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Staging is one thing that can tip the scales in favor of a home seller. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Staging is one thing that can tip the scales in favor of a home seller. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Conversation With Prime West Mortgage’s Tom Bartosh</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-conversation-with-prime-west-mortgages-tom-bartosh.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-05 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Interview+with+Tom+Bartosh+With+Prime+West+Mortgage+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m delighted to be joined by Tom Bartosh with Prime West Mortgage to talk a little bit about the lending world. 

I’ve been working with Tom for probably about six years now. He’s one of our preferred lenders for a reason. He has closed every transaction on time, every time. Not only does that show he’s on top of the ball, but it also shows that he’s a joy to work with.

Tom has been in the business since 1987. He loves what he does. He loves helping people through the mortgage process, and he loves to see closings. He makes the whole process fun.

“If Tom sends me a pre-approval letter for a buyer, I know that it is golden.”

How is he able to close on time, every time? It all starts off with his loan application process. It’s a thorough document that takes into account the entire picture of the buyer. He’s also an expert in all of the different loan programs that are available out there. 

If Tom sends me a pre-approval letter for a buyer, I know that it is golden. Now the ball is in my court to find them the best possible home, and they’ll take over from there. Oftentimes, Tom and his team are ready to close early, which is always a fantastic surprise.

Right now, Tom has a lot of different loan programs available for first-time homebuyers. There are grants, low down payment options, and much more. There are about five different programs that Tom has been utilizing. Tom loves working with first-time buyers and seeing the look on their faces at the end when their home closes.

Although Tom is an expert himself, he couldn’t do what he does without his team. His loan processor, Tammy, has been working with him for 25 years and is an integral part of his process.

If you have any questions for Tom or you’re curious about what kind of home you can afford, give him a call at (972) 935-9200 or send him an email to tbartosh@primewestcorp.com.

If you have any other questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Interview+with+Tom+Bartosh+With+Prime+West+Mortgage+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Interview+with+Tom+Bartosh+With+Prime+West+Mortgage+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In order to give you some greater insight into the lending process, I recently met with Tom Bartosh of Prime West Mortgage to discuss how he (and other mortgage experts) help people achieve their home buying goals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In order to give you some greater insight into the lending process, I recently met with Tom Bartosh of Prime West Mortgage to discuss how he (and other mortgage experts) help people achieve their home buying goals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Happening in Ellis County Real Estate Today?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-in-ellis-county-real-estate-today.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-27 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+miss+this+window+of+opportunity+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

The market is beginning to heat up in Ellis County, and recent data definitely reflects this.

For one thing, inventory remains low. With just 2.6 months’ worth of homes available on the market, sellers are in a prime position to sell quickly and for top dollar. Even at this comparatively low level of inventory, though, buyers are beginning to gain some leverage. The number of available listings has risen since last year, while the total number of closed home sales is actually down.

“Take advantage of these market conditions while they last.”

Also, while the average sales price has gone up since 2018, the list-to-sales price ratio has dropped. This, in conjunction with the fact that listings are taking longer to sell, indicates that sellers now need to be more flexible if they want to strike a deal. 

The bottom line is to take advantage of these market conditions while they last. We’ve hit the peak of the real estate cycle, so don’t delay. 

If you have any other questions, would like more information, or are curious about how I can help you make the most of your real estate goals, feel free to give me or my team a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+miss+this+window+of+opportunity+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+miss+this+window+of+opportunity+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A lot can change in one year, and this is certainly true of our market. In this quick market update, we’ll share how local real estate conditions have changed and what these developments mean for your goals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A lot can change in one year, and this is certainly true of our market. In this quick market update, we’ll share how local real estate conditions have changed and what these developments mean for your goals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Do’s and Don’ts of Prepping Your Home for the Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-dos-and-donts-of-prepping-your-home-for-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-06 08:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Dos+and+DonTs+of+Making+Your+Home+Market-Ready+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a seller this spring, there are a few do’s and don’ts to be aware of if you’re prepping your home to sell quickly and for top dollar in our real estate market. 

For your convenience, I’ve timestamped all the do’s and don’ts you need to remember from the video above so you can skip ahead at your leisure. In each section, I’ll also explain why each one qualifies as a “do” or “don’t”:

0:47—Do: focus on curb appeal projects2:19—Do: make bathroom updates 2:51—Do: install new windows 3:40—Don’t: pay for extensive professional landscaping 4:06—Don’t: install a new roof, gutters, sprinklers, or HVAC unit5:12—Don’t: add a swimming pool and/or personal spa 5:42—Don’t: paint the house6:10—Don’t: install solar panels 

If you’d like to talk more about prepping your home for sale or if you’re ready to start the home sale process, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be more than happy to give you a free home valuation and sit down for a consultation. 

As always, if you have any other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I look forward to speaking with you. 

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Dos+and+DonTs+of+Making+Your+Home+Market-Ready+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Dos+and+DonTs+of+Making+Your+Home+Market-Ready+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re getting ready to sell this spring, there are a few do’s and don’ts of prepping your home for the market that you need to be aware of.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re getting ready to sell this spring, there are a few do’s and don’ts of prepping your home for the market that you need to be aware of.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Different Relationships You Can Have With a Real Estate Agent</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-different-relationships-you-can-have-with-a-real-estate-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-25 12:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Closer+Look+at+Agent-Client+Relationships+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

One of our frequently most asked questions is, “How do we hire you as a real estate agent and how does that relationship work?” Therefore, we’re diving into agency relationships today. Here are the three most common relationships that people have with a real estate agent:

1. The listing agent. This person represents the best interest of the homeowner only. They market the home for sale, schedule showings.

“An intermediary transaction can be the easiest, most seamless transaction possible.”

2. The buyer’s agent. This person represented the best interests of the buyer only. They can advise you on how to make offers, where to find homes, and help you get the best terms possible.

3. Intermediary. This person represents both a buyer and seller in a transaction as long as both parties are consenting. It has to be a written agreement and sometimes these can be the easiest, most seamless transactions. In our brokerage, an intermediary is chosen for each side of the transaction. We will make sure the transaction is done correctly and without a lot of hassle.

I’m happy to be able to answer this question today and I’m always happy to answer any more of them that you have. Just give me a call or send me an email any time. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Closer+Look+at+Agent-Client+Relationships+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Closer+Look+at+Agent-Client+Relationships+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A lot of our clients are curious about how relationships with agents are supposed to work. We’ll explore that topic today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A lot of our clients are curious about how relationships with agents are supposed to work. We’ll explore that topic today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Home Buying Process in a Nutshell</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-home-buying-process-in-a-nutshell.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-11 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Home+Buying+Process+Explained+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Buying a home can be complicated even for seasoned homebuyers, but this is especially true for first-timers pursuing their dreams of homeownership. Today we’ll break down the home buying process into steps so that the inexperienced can know what they have to look forward to.

For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps below so that you can navigate our discussion in the video above at your leisure.

0:37—Picking the right Realtor to work with1:28—Picking a quality loan officer3:21—Listing out your wants and needs4:44—Going out to look at properties5:29—Upfront fees to expect:


  5:50—Earnest money
  6:30—Option money
  7:15—Inspection fee
  8:05—Appraisal fees


What you learned today is the home buying process in a nutshell, but if you’d like more detailed information, contact me today to schedule a consultation.

I’d be more than happy to sit down, discuss the process with you, and, more importantly, show you sample contracts and more so that when it comes time for you to begin the home buying journey, you’re not lost in a foreign world. I want to help you be comfortable making the decisions that you need to make for your family’s future.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Home+Buying+Process+Explained+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+The+Home+Buying+Process+Explained+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today we’ll be giving a shoutout to first-time homebuyers by providing tips and advice about how to navigate the process of purchasing a home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today we’ll be giving a shoutout to first-time homebuyers by providing tips and advice about how to navigate the process of purchasing a home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Your 2019 Market Forecast for Ellis County and the DFW Metro Area</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-2019-market-forecast-for-ellis-county-and-the-dfw-metro-area.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-08 14:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+in+Store+for+the+Rest+of+Our+2019+Market_+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

What can buyers and sellers expect from the rest of our 2019 market here in Ellis County and in the DFW Metro area?

First, let’s look at the current market statistics in Ellis County. We have 2.5 months of inventory, which means we’re still in a strong seller’s market. However, the tide is starting to turn in favor of buyers. This means if you’re a seller and you’ve been sitting on the fence, now is the time to capitalize on current conditions. 

Furthermore, the average days on market is 60 days, and the list-to-sale price ratio is 96% (for our clients, though, the average list-to-sale price ratio is 99%). I’ve been selling real estate for over 25 years, and this has been one of the craziest markets I’ve ever seen. What I love about it is buyers have been able to buy homes at top dollar and then sell them later for an additional profit—even with Realtor fees.

“I’ve been selling real estate for over 25 years, and this has been one of the craziest markets I’ve ever seen.”

Now, in terms of our broader DFW Metro market, there are four trends buyers and sellers need to be aware of in 2019, according to Realtor.com:


  More homes on the market. Additionally, luxury homes will stay on the market longer, which means sellers in the higher price ranges will need to be more creative to get their home sold in a timely manner.  
  Shrinking affordability. We’ve seen a ton of economic growth in the DFW metroplex recently, but moving forward, affordability will become an issue for buyers, especially in the $250,000-and-under price range. When you combine this trend with rising interest rates, first-time buyers run the risk of getting priced out of the market. 
  Changes in buyer demographics. Last year, 45% of all homebuyers were millennials (Gen Xers made up 36%, and baby boomers accounted for 17%). The buyers who will really be able to capitalize on the 2019 market are move-up buyers, because they’ll be able to use the equity they’ve built up as their current homes have appreciated and roll that equity into their next homes. 
  The new tax law. Obviously we won’t know the full extent of this law’s impact until after April 15, but it’s still something to keep an eye on in terms of what kind of mortgage deductions you can make. 


Overall, our market is still performing well. If you’re a seller, as I said, there’s no better time to enter the market than right now. If you’re a buyer, I’d advise you to jump into the market as well. Interest rates are climbing, but they’ve stalled a bit recently and are hovering around 4.375%, which is still historically low. 

Whether you’re buying or selling, don’t hesitate to give my team a call so we can help you accomplish all of your real estate goals. If you have any other questions about our market, feel free to reach out to us as well. We’d love to speak to you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+in+Store+for+the+Rest+of+Our+2019+Market_+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Whats+in+Store+for+the+Rest+of+Our+2019+Market_+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re still in a strong seller’s market, but as you’ll see, conditions are starting to favor buyers as we move forward in 2019.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re still in a strong seller’s market, but as you’ll see, conditions are starting to favor buyers as we move forward in 2019.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Buy a New Construction Home Without an Agent</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-buy-a-new-construction-home-without-an-agent.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-25 14:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+Walk+into+a+New+Construction+Home+Alone+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Happy New Year! Our team has already heard from an incredible number of buyers and sellers seeking our help with their 2019 real estate goals, and we’re so excited to make this year our best yet. 

In addition to this, we’re also excited to continue bringing you the hottest tips from our market. And, today, we’ll be covering a particularly important one: Hire a Realtor when you buy new construction. 

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific sections at your leisure: 

0:47 - Do buyers really need representation during a new home purchase?

2:36 - How having representation can benefit your new construction purchase

3:05 - The truth about the on-site agent

4:03 - The complexity of a new construction purchase

5:06 - How to protect your best interests during a new construction purchase

6:01 - Is forgoing representation actually less expensive?

6:34 - How and why you should contact our team

7:03 - How to get your real estate questions answered in a future video

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+Walk+into+a+New+Construction+Home+Alone+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+Walk+into+a+New+Construction+Home+Alone+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re purchasing a new construction home, do you still need an agent working on your behalf? Actually, yes—and today we’ll explain why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re purchasing a new construction home, do you still need an agent working on your behalf? Actually, yes—and today we’ll explain why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Merry Christmas and Happy New Year!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/merry-christmas-and-happy-new-year.html</link>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-13 16:03:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Wish+You+a+Merry+Christmas.mp4</guid>
        <description>
We hope you and your family have a great holiday. May the Christmas season fill your home with joy. It truly brings us joy to help you make your real estate dreams a reality. Thank you for working with us. We wouldn’t be where we are today without your help. As always, if you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’re here to help you in any way we can. Have a fantastic Christmas and we’ll see you in the new year! To hear my full message, watch this short video.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Wish+You+a+Merry+Christmas.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Krissy+Mireles/2019/September/Waxahachie%2C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Wish+You+a+Merry+Christmas.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It truly brings us joy to help you make your real estate dreams a reality. Thank you for working with us. We wouldn’t be where we are today without your help.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It truly brings us joy to help you make your real estate dreams a reality. Thank you for working with us. We wouldn’t be where we are today without your help.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Everything You Need to Know About Our Current Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/everything-you-need-to-know-about-our-current-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Krissy Mireles</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-04 16:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Krissy+Mireles/Waxahachie%252C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Your+Market+Questions+Answered.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Over the last couple of years, our local real estate market has been phenomenal. We’ve seen exponential growth. With that in mind, today we’re going to outline what exactly has been going on. 

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure: 

1:35 - Are we in a buyer’s market or a seller’s market right now?

2:24 - What does the current housing inventory look like?

3:18 - How does current inventory affect local home values?

“Ellis County is currently experiencing a seller’s market”

3:34 - What do the interest rates look like?

4:34 - When is the best time to enter the market to maximize purchasing power?

4:50 - What does all of this information mean for buyers and sellers?

5:40 - What questions should buyers ask while house hunting?

5:48 - House hunting question No. 1: How is the neighborhood or area?

6:33 - House hunting question No. 2: How are the schools?

7:18 - House hunting question No. 3: What are the home’s average utility bills?

9:01 - How to contact us about any other questions you have. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Krissy+Mireles/Waxahachie%252C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Your+Market+Questions+Answered.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Krissy+Mireles/Waxahachie%252C+TX+Real+Estate+Agent-+Your+Market+Questions+Answered.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our local market has seen some incredible growth, so today we’ll be sharing what you can do to make the most of it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Krissy Mireles</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our local market has seen some incredible growth, so today we’ll be sharing what you can do to make the most of it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Ellis County, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Krissy Mireles</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Krissy Mireles</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Holmquist & Associates Realty - your professional Ellis County Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
